# Nick Leslie

Full Stack Software Engineer and Engineering People Leader

🕲 Washington, District of Columbia, United States, 20009 ၆ 202 400 1892 🕲 ncpleslie@gmail.com & https://nickleslie.dev

in nicholas-leslie 🕥 ncpleslie

# Summary

I am a **Full-Stack Software Engineer, Web Developer** and an **Engineering People Leader** with expertise in web development, automation, and cloud services. With a track record of always exploring new technologies and delivering outstanding applications for my clients.

# Experience

### Engineering People Leader | September 2022 - August 2023

Jade Software Corporation

- Supported a team of Software Engineers by providing mentorship, leadership, communication, and training. Through regular one-on-ones, structured training sessions and code reviews
- Participated in software development projects, from pre-sales, design, development and delivery. Engaging with clients throughout the software development lifecycle
- Provided technical expertise and guidance across the company, supporting innovation and improvement as the go-to domain expert on numerous technologies and projects

### Software Engineer | July 2020 - September 2022

Jade Software Corporation

- Contributed to an agile, cross-functional team, using the Scrum methodology to develop cloud-native web applications for global clients
- Collaborated across the software development lifecycle, managing requirements, API design, database design, implementation, testing, code reviews, and deployment through CI/CD pipelines. Using source control
- Maintained client satisfaction through proactive engagement, gathering requirements, and delivering regular progress updates to clients and stakeholders

# Computer Vision Intern | December 2019 - February 2020

Jade Software Corporation

 Developed a computer vision application for running on the Edge to enhance the capabilities of security cameras. Allowing them to perform license plate recognition, object tracking and detection. Using GCP Firebase, Python, OpenCV, and OpenVino

### **Projects**

#### Air New Zealand Crew Claims Portal

Led a team to develop a secure web portal for submitting expense claims for pilots and crew members. Using **TypeScript, Vue 3, Tailwind, Vitest, NodeJS, GitHub**. **CI/CD** pipeline with **GitHub Actions**. Deployed to **Azure** with **Azure Active Directory, API-M,** and **Static Web Apps** 

### Skipton Document Management System

Developed a document storage system for the regulated financial sector. Manages 180M+ documents, ingesting millions monthly. Developed with TypeScript, Vue3, Tailwind, C#, .Net, EF Core, xUnit. Deployed on Azure with CosmosDB NoSQL and Blob Storage

https://www.jadeworld.com/services/jade-digital/our-clients/skipton-case-study

### DB Cargo Employee Hub

Full-stack developer in a team that developed a secure **Android** application for a DB Cargo UK to access training resources, documentation, schedules, etc. Domain and **REST** API designed with **UML**. Using **C#, Xamarin, EF Core, Domain-Driven Design, .NET, SQLite**, and **MSSQL** 

 ${\boldsymbol{\mathcal{O}}}\ \ \text{https://www.jadeworld.com/services/jade-digital/our-clients/db-cargo-uk-case-study}$ 

## **Zurich Insurance Calculator**

Developed a white-labeled, configuration-driven insurance (Life, TPD) calculator for Zurich Insurance, Australia. Using **Angular** and **TypeScript** for frontend and **C#**, .**NET** for the backend. Deployed to **Azure** with **App Service** and **CosmosDB** 

₱ https://zurich.zurichcalculators.net/

## **WMATA Train Tracker**

Personally developed a WMATA train tracking application is for monitoring the metro train arrival times in the DMV area. Built with **Go**, **Wails**, **SOLC**, **SOLite**, **TypeScript**, **Vue 3**, **Tailwind**, **Nuxt 3**, **tRPC**, **Zod**, and **GitHub Actions** 

A https://github.com/ncpleslie/wmata-train-tracker

#### Draw For Them

Personally developed an ephemeral image sharing and drawing application. Built with NextJS, TypeScript, React, Jest, FabricJS, tRPC, NextAuth, WebSockets, Postgres, and Prisma

https://github.com/ncpleslie/draw-for-them

# Education

Ara Institute of Canterbury
Major in Software Engineering
First Class with Distinction